<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HighwayHead</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 16:56:23 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 16:56:23 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Unreasonable Effectiveness of Mathematics in the Natural Sciences</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Just as there are odors that dogs can smell and we cannot, as well as sounds that dogs can hear and we cannot, so too there are wavelengths of light we cannot see and flavors we cannot taste. Why then, given our brains wired the way they are, does the remark ‘Perhaps there are thoughts we cannot think,’ surprise you? Evolution, so far, may possibly have blocked us from being able to think in some directions; there could be unthinkable thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dartmouth.edu/~matc/MathDrama/reading/Hamming.html&quot;&gt;The Unreasonable Effectiveness of Mathematics in the Natural Sciences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 16:59:30 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/auto/2014/12/23/the-unreasonable-effectiveness-of-mathematics-in-the-natural-sciences/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/auto/2014/12/23/the-unreasonable-effectiveness-of-mathematics-in-the-natural-sciences/</guid>
        
        
        <category>auto</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Daring Fireball: Yahoo&#39;s Decline</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I would argue that Yahoo lost its way early. Yahoo was an amazing, awesome resource when it first appeared, as a directory to cool websites. Arguably, the  directory to cool websites. It was hard to find the good stuff on the early web, and Yahoo created a map. Their whole reason for being was to serve as a starting point that sent you elsewhere. Then came portals. The portal strategy was the opposite of the directory strategy — it was about keeping people on Yahoo’s site, instead of sending them elsewhere. It was lucrative for a while, but ran its course. And it turned out that the web quickly became too large, far too large, for a human-curated directory to map more than a fraction of it. The only way to index the web was algorithmically, as a search engine. And one search engine stood head and shoulders above all others: Google. Yahoo reportedly had an opportunity to buy Google in 2002 for $5 billion . Yahoo, under the leadership of CEO Terry Semel, declined. And that was the end of Yahoo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/2014/12/yahoo_decline&quot;&gt;Daring Fireball: Yahoo’s Decline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 11:26:35 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/auto/2014/12/18/daring-fireball-yahoos-decline/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/auto/2014/12/18/daring-fireball-yahoos-decline/</guid>
        
        
        <category>auto</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How You Know</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Reading and experience train your model of the world. And even if you forget the experience or what you read, its effect on your model of the world persists. Your mind is like a compiled program you’ve lost the source of. It works, but you don’t know why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/know.html&quot;&gt;How You Know&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 12:14:48 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/auto/2014/12/16/how-you-know/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/auto/2014/12/16/how-you-know/</guid>
        
        
        <category>auto</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our quantum reality problem – Adrian Kent – Aeon</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The best present ideas for addressing the quantum reality problem are at least as crude and problematic as Bohr’s model of the atom. Nature is far richer than our imaginations, and we will almost certainly need new experimental data to take our understanding of quantum reality further. If the past is any guide, it should be an extraordinarily interesting scientific journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aeon.co/magazine/science/our-quantum-reality-problem/&quot;&gt;Our quantum reality problem – Adrian Kent – Aeon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 12:44:15 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/auto/2014/12/08/our-quantum-reality-problem--adrian-kent--aeon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/auto/2014/12/08/our-quantum-reality-problem--adrian-kent--aeon/</guid>
        
        
        <category>auto</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Peering Into The Minds Of The 4.3 Billion Unconnected | TechCrunch</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I can relate to this skepticism since I too was once on that side of the fence. It is tempting to presume that mobile devices and basic Internet services are plug-and-play; that they have perfectly optimized their user experiences and can successfully onboard anyone, any time, any day. But the reality is we live in a world where 4.3 billion people have never experienced the Internet. These are people who mostly can’t tell what the X at the top-right of the screen does, or what “sign up” means, or what a username and password are, or that cancel buttons are red or gray, or how a QWERTY keyboard works, or how to sign up for mobile data, or why should one even do it in the first place. All this represents a highly complex, multifaceted problem and the payoff of ultimately solving it will fundamentally change us as a species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2014/11/29/peering-into-the-minds-of-the-4-3-billion-unconnected/&quot;&gt;Peering Into The Minds Of The 4.3 Billion Unconnected - TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 10:17:20 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/auto/2014/12/08/peering-into-the-minds-of-the-4.3-billion-unconnected--techcrunch/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/auto/2014/12/08/peering-into-the-minds-of-the-4.3-billion-unconnected--techcrunch/</guid>
        
        
        <category>auto</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to hire a product manager - by Ken Norton</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Product management is a weird discipline full of oddballs and rejects that never quite fit in anywhere else. For my part, I loved the technical challenges of engineering but despised the coding. I liked solving problems, but I hated having other people tell me what to do. I wanted to be a part of the strategic decisions, I wanted to own  the product. Marketing appealed to my creativity, but I knew I’d dislike being too far away from the technology. Engineers respected me, but knew my heart was elsewhere and generally thought I was too ‘marketing-ish.’ People like me naturally gravitate to product management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kennethnorton.com/essays/productmanager.html&quot;&gt;How to hire a product manager - by Ken Norton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 17:19:16 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/auto/2014/12/05/how-to-hire-a-product-manager-by-ken-norton/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/auto/2014/12/05/how-to-hire-a-product-manager-by-ken-norton/</guid>
        
        
        <category>auto</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Demis Hassabis, Founder of DeepMind Technologies and Artificial-Intelligence Wunderkind at Google, Wants Machines to Think Like Us | MIT Technology Review</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;rtificial intelligence researchers have been tinkering with reinforcement learning for decades. But until DeepMind’s Atari demo, no one had built a system capable of learning anything nearly as complex as how to play a computer game, says Hassabis. One reason it was possible was a trick borrowed from his favorite area of the brain. Part of the Atari-playing software’s learning process involved replaying its past experiences over and over to try and extract the most accurate hints on what it should do in the future. “That’s something that we know the brain does,” says Hassabis. “When you go to sleep your hippocampus replays the memory of the day back to your cortex.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.technologyreview.com/news/532876/googles-intelligence-designer/&quot;&gt;Demis Hassabis, Founder of DeepMind Technologies and Artificial-Intelligence Wunderkind at Google, Wants Machines to Think Like Us - MIT Technology Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 16:06:06 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/auto/2014/12/04/demis-hassabis-founder-of-deepmind-technologies-and-artificial-intelligence-wunderkind-at-google-wants-machines-to-think-like-us--mit-technology-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/auto/2014/12/04/demis-hassabis-founder-of-deepmind-technologies-and-artificial-intelligence-wunderkind-at-google-wants-machines-to-think-like-us--mit-technology-review/</guid>
        
        
        <category>auto</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New questions in mobile — Benedict Evans</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Part of the reason for Google to change what ‘Android’ means is control, but a deeper one is to change the smartphone interaction model. It’s always been obvious that apps were a structural problem for Google, since their content is hidden from search and more importantly unlinkable from search results, paid or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What we can see happening now are shifts in the layers of aggregation and discovery. We’ve gone from everything being bundled within the web browser, and then accessed through Google (itself a bundle) to app icons unbundling specific content from the web. At the same time apps bundle all the content from one site and make it impossible to link directly to a specific page. Hence we now have both deep linking, which lets you get into the silo, and rich actionable notifications unbundling pieces of content out of the silo. And we also have cards  floating around (delivered in many different ways) as another unbundling metaphor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Across all of this, and far more important, we are now well on our way to having some 3.5bn to 4bn people on earth with a smartphone - there are probably 2bn today, and close to 4bn people with a mobile phone (the number of duplicate SIMs makes the number of active connection closer to 6bn). This compares to around 1.6bn PCs, of which roughly half are consumer and half corporate. So there will be something like 5 times more smartphones than consumer PCs, and those devices are always with you and, with all their apps and sensors, are much more sophisticated than PCs ever were, seen as internet devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ben-evans.com/benedictevans/2014/11/20/time-for-new-questions-in-mobile&quot;&gt;New questions in mobile — Benedict Evans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 10:14:15 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/auto/2014/12/04/new-questions-in-mobile--benedict-evans/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/auto/2014/12/04/new-questions-in-mobile--benedict-evans/</guid>
        
        
        <category>auto</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Seven plus or minus two</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Limiting the number of menu tabs or the number of items in a dropdown list to the George Miller’s magic number 7 is a false constraint. Miller’s original theory argues that people can keep no more than 7 (plus or minus 2) items in their short-term memory. On a webpage, however, the information is visually present, people don’t have to memorize anything and therefore can easily manage broader choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://uxmyths.com/post/931925744/myth-23-choices-should-always-be-limited-to-seven&quot;&gt;Seven plus or minus two&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 17:00:13 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/auto/2014/11/24/seven-plus-or-minus-two/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/auto/2014/11/24/seven-plus-or-minus-two/</guid>
        
        
        <category>auto</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>App-pocalypse Now</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Unless you’re careful to build equivalent apps in all those places, it’s like having multiple parallel Internets. ‘No, sorry, it’s not available on that Internet, only the iOS phone Internet.’ Or even worse, only on the United States iOS phone Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;natural web conveniences like opening links in new tabs, sharing links, the back button, searching within the page, and zooming in and out are available inconsistently, if at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If there’s one thing I love about tablet and phone design it’s that their small screens and touch interfaces force people to think simpler&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m waiting for something that will unify the world of apps and make manually going to an App Store to find a new app as weird as typing in a URL to find a new website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.codinghorror.com/app-pocalypse-now/&quot;&gt;App-pocalypse Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 10:33:13 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/auto/2014/11/17/app-pocalypse-now/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/auto/2014/11/17/app-pocalypse-now/</guid>
        
        
        <category>auto</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
